SAURABH KUMAR

College Station, Texas

thesaurabh@tamu.edu

📞 (979)-587-4387

Objective: Masters candidate in Computer Science with 5 years of work experience as a Software Developer in leading multinational product companies. Seeking to leverage my academic knowledge & work experience to fill the Senior Software Developer position in your company. I also possess professional leadership experience that will prove to be valuable for this position.

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University, College Station, TX

Aug 2017 - May 2019

Master of Computer Science

GPA: 3.5/4

Courses: Distributed & Cloud Computing, Parallel Computing, Deep Learning, Software Engineering, Artificial Intelligence

Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), B.H.U

July 2008 – May 2012

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering

GPA: 3.52/4.0

Courses: Operating Systems, Algorithms, Data Structures, Computer Architecture, Software Engineering, Networking

TECHNICAL SKILLS & AREA OF INTEREST

- C/C++, gdb, Python, csh/bash scripting, Perl, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, Perforce, Agile, numpy, scipy, Sk-learn, nltk, unix/linux
- Machine Learning, Distributed & Cloud Computing, Software Engineering, Systems Engineering, Algorithms & Data Structures

WORK EXPERIENCE (5 years)

Mentor, A Siemens Business (https://www.mentor.com)

Noida, India

Lead Member of Technical Staff (R&D), DVT-Questa

July 2016 – April 2017

- Designed and implemented post synthesis UPF support in FPGA prototyping compiler using C++. Enabled power aware verification of SoC & ASIC designs on FPGA. Created SRS, architecture/implementation specs & Unit/Functional Testing
- Proposed feature plans, future roadmaps, created design documents, performed code reviews and progress monitoring of the Compiler Driver Software.

Senior Member of Technical Staff (R&D), DVT-Questa

Aug 2013 - July 2016

- Implemented VHDL-93 & VHDL-2008 constructs in the VHDL Compiler of Questa Visualizer debugger using C/C++
- Designed & implemented VHDL RTL encryption mechanism in Compiler as per IEEE-1735 standards for IP protection.
- Developed the compiler driver of FPGA prototyping system from scratch using C++. Designed its interface, functional behavior & architecture. Implemented task distribution, parallel execution and synchronization over SGE, LSF and machine list in shared memory subsystem. Achieved multifold gain in run time efficiency. Used Perforce for SCM & Bugzilla for defects.

NetApp Inc. (https://www.netapp.com)

Bangalore, India

Member of Technical Staff 1 (R&D), Array Products Group

July 2012 – July 2013

 Added Storage Array Discovery & Support Bundle Collection features in Enterprise Storage Array management software called SANtricity in C++. Developed CLI programs to implement Volume Management, Firmware Inventory and Array Discovery features in C++ which were distributed with SDK package.

Software Engineering Intern, Dedupe, Data ONTAP

May 2011 – July 2011

• Built a CLI tool using Python to verify the integrity of the fingerprint database to identify potential metadata corruption of Dedupe FPDB. This tool was used to identify situations that could lead to data loss during deduplication.

Infogile Technologies (P) Limited

Gurgaon, India

Software Engineering Intern, Creative Genes

May 2010 – July 2010

• Developed & tested a J2ME mobile Brochure creator. Implemented functionalities for Buffering and streaming media, XML parser, live feeds and Facebook integration using KXML and Facebook mobile API.

PROJECTS

- **B.Tech Project:** Simulation for RCS(Radar Cross Section) calculation of 3D Targets using parallel implementation of ADI-DTD Algorithm. Used parallel algorithms to distribute 3D matrix multiplication jobs on SGI Altix 12 node server. **Technologies used:** C++, OpenMP, MPI, LAM. **Tools Used:** SGI Altix Server, AutoCAD
- Web Development: Designed & built a dynamic web application using Django/python framework for Centre of Phage Technologies at Texas A&M. Followed BDD using behave Django, TDD for Coverage, Agile using Pivotal, Git for SCM on GitHub.

ASSISTANTSHIPS

Texas A&M University

College Station, Texas

Graduate Assistant

Fall 2017/ Spring 2018

 Developed an Autograding framework to automatically evaluate & grade C++ programs against rubrics such as correctness, templates and behavior for Dept. of CSE, Texas A&M University. Supervised a C++ class and assisted with course curriculum.

EXTRACURRICULAR

Volunteer Work, Fitness enthusiast, Reader, Acoustic Guitar player, cooking & Traveling.